<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Even More About Me on Joseph Buiteweg</title>
    <link>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/about/</link>
    <description>Joseph Buiteweg (Even More About Me)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 18:37:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/about/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/about/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-your-website-pink&#34;&gt;Why is your website pink?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is pink because I really like pink and pastel colors. I appreciate their friendly and comforting qualities, both of which I try to bring to my interactions with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also found the stigmas regarding cis-gendered straight men and the color pink silly and unfair, so I say we &lt;strong&gt;yeet em&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; to the curb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-you-have-a-website--blog&#34;&gt;Why do you have a website / blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten tons of help and useful info from other peoples&amp;rsquo; programming blogs and articles, and I want to give back in a similar way. I also love teaching and helping others, so I view this site as the perfect outlet for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not born knowing what I know - other people have helped me get to where I am. It&amp;rsquo;s important us engineers acknowledge our struggles, as it helps comfort those who face the same difficulty in learning the skills needed in our respective fields. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that documenting my struggles with new things I learn will help on this front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people in tech have been saved by reading somebody else&amp;rsquo;s encounter with the esoteric and pain-staking problem they&amp;rsquo;re tackling. StackOverflow, various StackExchange sites, people&amp;rsquo;s blogs, spec-sheets, and user documentation are all crucial to the landscape of learning software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/wisdom_of_the_ancients.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;CC BY-NC 2.5&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;CC BY-NC 2.5&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xe1TZaElTAs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;
 by Clay Shirky sums it up nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of Clay referring to everyone as &amp;ldquo;guys&amp;rdquo;. I believe &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;engineers&amp;rdquo; is often a better choice. The word hacker also makes me cringe, but the sentiment is said well otherwise. The talk shows that it&amp;rsquo;s from 2007 with its references, as &lt;code&gt;perl&lt;/code&gt; is relatively old. Do note this is just my opinion, but I believe most people will tell you Python and Ruby are much more sensible choices in the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Is-Perl-still-relevant-in-2020?share=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt;
. )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;these-are-all-just-your-opinions-right&#34;&gt;These are all just your opinions, right?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes everything on this site is my own personal opinion and doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reflect that of whoever employs me at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of programming and tech is quite subjective with only some absolutes. The above disclaimer is quite important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you disagree with the content you see here don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to reach out. I love discussing most all topics related to tech, even the most subjective ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>