<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interviewing on Joey Buiteweg</title>
    <link>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/categories/interviewing/</link>
    <description>Joey Buiteweg (interviewing)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/categories/interviewing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercism: A Community-Driven Alternative to Leetcode</title>
      <link>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/blog/exercism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.josephbuiteweg.com/blog/exercism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whiteboard-questions&#34;&gt;Whiteboard Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has interviewed for a software engineering position has no doubt spent some time practicing &amp;ldquo;whiteboard questions&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whiteboard questions are normally datastructures and algorithms-oriented programming questions meant to assess technical competency. I personally think such questions fall short in evaluating the effectiveness of an engineer, but they are still prevalent nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not the interviewing company does these types of technical questions depends on the company. It is well known though, that Facebook, Amazon, Apple, Netflix and Google (colloquially known as &amp;ldquo;FAANG&amp;rdquo;) ask these kinds of questions in their interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Leetcode&lt;/a&gt;
, cringy name and all, is a popular site for practicing such whiteboard questions. You work on example problems and submit them, after which you solution is evaluated for performance and correctness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Leetcode falls short in its lack of potential feedback from an actual human being. Interviewers place strong perference on code readability and being able to understand your solution as you make it. &lt;strong&gt;Leetcode absolutely does not ensure either of these!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exercism&#34;&gt;Exercism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://exercism.io/&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exercism&lt;/a&gt;
, a great alternative or supplement to Leetcode for programming practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercism is entirely free, unlike Leetcode which requires purchasing a premium tier to access all problems, and provides the option to be mentored on improving your solutions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://exercism.io/become-a-mentor&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mentoring&lt;/a&gt;
 and receiving general input from others on your public solutions is a fantastic way to improve yourself as a teammate and engineer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not comfortable with this aspect of Exercism, mentoring and making your solutions public is entirely optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is Exercism a great tool for interview practice, it&amp;rsquo;s excellent for learning a new programming language as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve read and heard many success stories from engineers using Exercism to become fluent in a new programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently attended a Go Developer Network event and watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-eWTdp58uiY&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt;
, which is both a great example success story and how I learned about Exercism in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently started using Exercism and love it thus far. I especially like its command-line interface (CLI), and how everything is run on your machine, as opposed to some annoying and slow web-interface like Leetcode&amp;rsquo;s development environment. The free tier of Leetcode takes longer to compile, run and submit solutions, which is very unappealing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://exercism.io/profiles/joebb97&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my exercism profile&lt;/a&gt;
 as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/joebb97/exercism-solutions&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my repository&lt;/a&gt;
 with my solutions to various problems on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll join the community and make use of this wonderful resource!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>